http://www.tntech.edu/privacy/index.php

Website Privacy
Tennessee Tech recognizes the concerns of individuals regarding privacy and online
data collection. We strive to respect and protect the privacy expectations of our
website visitors. All websites collect some information regarding visitors. Types
of information collected are wide-ranging and are collected both passively (by the
web servers that host the websites) and actively (via user input through forms, surveys,
etc.).
Some of the information collected allows site owners to determine who a particular
visitor is and to track their behavior within and across a website domain. However,
most of the information collected cannot identify you as a particular individual and
is only collected in aggregate.
Websites within the Tennessee Tech website domain, tntech.edu, likewise collect information
regarding site visitors. This policy outlines the types of information (data) collected,
our methods for collecting data, and the reasons we collect data.
Gathering & Use of Information
Aggregate Information
The following are examples of information that may be collected in aggregate to provide
campus communicators, site owners, content managers, designers, and IT specialists
insight into visitor behavior for the purpose of improving University websites and
access to University information:
The Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer and name of the Internet domain
used to access the Internet;
IP addresses of websites linking directly to sites within the tntech.edu domain;
The date and time a site was accessed within the tntech.edu domain;
Pages visited (“requested”) during this session;
Web browser and operating system used to access a site within the tntech.edu domain;
and
Device used to access a site within the tntech.edu domain.
Tennessee Tech websites commonly use one of the following methods to collect this
data:
Cookies - Cookies are small pieces of data sent from our website(s) and stored in your web
browser. Accepting cookies allows visitors to set user preferences and otherwise enable
a more “personalized” experience with a website. Users may set preferences regarding
the storage of cookies within their individual web browsers which can also be used
to remove stored cookies.
Third-party Tracking (e.g. Google Analytics) - Many websites within the tntech.edu domain use Google Analytics to collect visitor
data in aggregate. This data is also collected using cookies set by Google. See Google’s
privacy and terms with regard to partner sites for more info: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/  Tennessee Tech may also transmit non-personal identifiable information (NPII) collected
by third-party tracking services (cookies) to other third parties (e.g. Facebook)
so that you may see messages from the University when you visit other websites outside
of the tntech.edu domain.
Server logs - All web servers collect very basic visitor information to monitor site usage and performance.
Personal Information
The following are examples of personal information that visitors may choose to share
with Tennessee Tech via a website interface (e.g. an online form or survey):
Name
E-mail address
Phone number
Mailing address
Subject matter interests
Date of high school graduation
The University may also collect personal information about you from third parties,
including trusted vendors, suppliers, and related companies. This is primarily done
for the purpose of recruiting students to attend the University.
If you have shared personal information with Tennessee Tech, we may use that information
to tailor services to you, to fulfill materials requests, to contact you, or to display
web content that may be of particular interest to you.
The University does not share personal information with third parties except:
As required by law;
As necessary to protect the University’s interests; and
With trusted vendors contracted by the University who have agreed to keep this information
confidential.
In these latter cases, we share relevant personal information with trusted vendors
to gain insight into ways we can improve your overall experience and otherwise further
your interest in our University.
We do not sell personal information to third parties.
Browsing Information and Tracking
Some websites within the tntech.edu domain may use third-party vendor re-marketing
tracking tools, such as the Google “AdWords” conversion tag and the Facebook “pixel,”
to serve targeted online advertisements about the University, its colleges, its events,
etc. These ads may appear within third-party services and/or on unrelated websites
across the internet. The third-party vendors who serve the ads use the information
they gather from cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to tailor advertisements
to you. This collected data may also be used by University communicators to measure
the success of online advertising campaigns (i.e. “ad conversion”).
Some of these re-marketing tools can potentially transmit personally identifiable
information to third parties and the University along with your browser history, particularly
if you are logged in to one of the services while browsing the internet (e.g. Facebook,
Google).
Opting Out
To opt out of the collection and use of information for ad targeting on Facebook and
other websites, you can use the Digital Advertising Alliance’s WebChoices Tool, which scans your browser for companies that are already serving you customized ads.
To opt out of Google's ad personalization, visit Google’s Ad Settings.
You can also opt out of “interest-based advertising” by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt out page.
Tennessee Tech and the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation
Tennessee Tech may be a data “controller” or “processor” with regard to certain activities
as defined under the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (“EU GDPR”).
Tennessee Tech is committed to protecting the rights of individuals in compliance
with the GDPR.
If you have a question regarding your rights as a data subject under GDPR, please
contact compliance@tntech.edu
Policy Updates and Changes
Technology used to access the internet and build websites changes nearly every day.
Likewise, the ways in which online data is generated and collected change frequently.
We reserve the right to update and make changes to this policy, and we encourage site
visitors to reference it periodically to familiarize themselves with its current terms.
